"Dinner's ready!"
"晚饭好了！"
Do you recognise that familiar call for everyone to gather round the table and tuck in?
你是否认得那熟悉的呼唤，召唤大家围坐在桌旁大快朵颐？
Whether it's a takeaway with friends or a family get-together during holiday seasons, humans have been eating together for thousands of years.
无论是和朋友一起吃外卖，还是在节日期间的家庭聚会，人类一起吃饭已经有数千年的历史了。
But why?
但这是为什么呢？
The discovery of fire may have kickstarted communal eating for our hunter-gatherer ancestors, according to primatologist Richard Wrangham.
根据灵长类动物学家理查德·兰厄姆的说法，火的发现可能使我们的狩猎采集祖先开始集体进食。
Cooking a meal all those years ago required a social group – you needed someone to hunt the food, someone to protect the food from thieves or predators, and of course, someone to cook.
在那些年代，做一顿饭需要一个社会群体——你需要有人去猎取食物，有人保护食物免受窃贼或捕食者的侵害，当然还需要有人来烹饪。
And once enjoying the feast, evolutionary psychologist Robin Dunbar speculates that the fire's bright light may have given the humans longer nights and provided great opportunities for bonding over food.
进化心理学家罗宾·邓巴推测，一旦开始享用盛宴，火的光亮可能给了人类更长的夜晚，并为通过食物建立联系提供了绝佳的机会。
But modern humans don't face the same threats as we used to – we can cook and eat a meal by ourselves.
但现代人类不再面临过去那样的威胁——我们可以自己做饭吃饭。
So why should we still make group meals a ritual?
那么，为什么我们还应该把集体用餐当作一种仪式呢？
In Dunbar's 2017 study 'Breaking Bread: the Functions of Social Eating', they found communal eating increased feelings of wellbeing and connectedness with the community.
在邓巴2017年的研究《分享面包：社交饮食的功能》中，他们发现集体进食增加了幸福感和与群体的联结感。
Despite this, the study found a third of weekday evening meals in the UK are eaten in isolation – the main cause being busy work schedules.
尽管如此，研究发现英国有三分之一的平日晚餐是独自吃的——主要原因是繁忙的工作日程。
Today's reality is that having meals together can be difficult.
如今的现实是，聚餐可能很困难。
Time management, fussy eaters, and family tensions are all things that can get in the way.
时间管理、挑食者和家庭矛盾都是障碍。
But, in an article about overthinking family meals, Susannah Ayre and colleagues write 'Five tips to ease the pressure', including dropping the need for perfection.
但是，在一篇关于过度思考家庭聚餐的文章中，苏珊娜·艾尔及其同事写了《减轻压力的五个小贴士》，包括放弃追求完美。"
"There is no shame in reheating a frozen meal" or "eating on a picnic rug in the living room".
加热冷冻食品没有什么可羞耻的"，或者"在客厅的野餐毯上吃饭"。
Sharing meals may look different today than it did for our ancestors, but the essence stays the same: food is more than just fuel.
如今分享餐食可能看起来与我们祖先的时代不同，但本质是一样的：食物不仅仅是供能食品。
It can be a way to connect, share stories and strengthen bonds.
它可以是一种联系、分享故事和强化关系的方式。